Guide to the Romanov Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Romanov collection
1894-1935
1907-1918
GEN MSS 313
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
12.8
(15 boxes)
The collection consists of letters, photographs, artwork, and autographs by or pertaining to the imperial family. Most of the correspondence is from members of the Russian imperial family to their friends Anna Vyrubova and Lili Dehn, and chiefly concerns details of everyday existence in captivity at T︠S︡arskoe Selo (T︠S︡arskoselʹskiĭ dvoret︠s︡), Tobol'sk, and Ekaterinburg, and news about mutual friends, with little specific reference to historical events. There are also a few letters to the Romanovs or third parties from members of the imperial entourage, including Grigori Rasputin. The six albums of family photographs (1908-1915) and accompanying loose photographs consist mainly of snapshots of the family's leisure activities and individual and group portraits. These are accompanied by an autograph album and a few pieces of artwork.
Romanov, House of
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Robert D. Brewster, 1951, 1983. The letters to Anna Vyrubova (in Series I) and the photo albums (in Series II) were acquired by Brewster from Anna Vyrubova, a friend of the Romanov family.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 10-15: ‡a Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
CHRONOLOGY
This chronology provides a basic guide, for reference purposes, to events of immediate relevance to the time period covered by materials in the collection.
1868 6/18 May Birth of future Emperor Nicholas II
1872 6 Jun Birth of Princess of Alix of Hesse-Darmstadt, future Empress Alexandra
1894 14/26 Nov Marriage of Nicholas and Alexandra
1896 14/26 May Coronation of Emperor Nicholas II
1895 3/15 Nov Birth of Ol'ga Nikolaevna
1897 29 May/10 Jun Birth of Tat'iana Nikolaevna
1899 14/26 Jun Birth of Mariia Nikolaevna
1901 5/18 Jun Birth of Anastasiia Nikolaevna
1904 30 Jul/12 Aug Birth of Aleksei Nikolaevich
1914 19 Jul/1 Aug Germany declares war on Russia
1916 17/30 Dec Murder of Rasputin (b. 1864)
1917 22 Feb/7 Mar Nicholas II returns to Mogilev from TSarskoe Selo
1917 23 Feb/8 Mar Strikes and unrest ensue in Petrograd on International Women's Day
1917 28 Feb/13 Mar Nicholas II, unable reach TSarskoe Selo, goes to Pskov
1917 2/15 Mar Nicholas II abdicates for himself and for his son in favor of his brother Mikhail, who refuses the throne the next day
1917 8/20 Mar Aleksandra placed under house arrest at TSarskoe Selo
1917 7/20 Mar Nicholas was arrested at GHQ-Mogilev
1917 1/14 Aug Imperial family evacuated to Tobol'sk via Tiumen'
1917 6/19 Aug Imperial family arrives in Tobol'sk
1917 25 Aug/7 Sep Anna Vyrubova detained in Petrograd
1917 1/14 Sep Vasilii Pankratov arrives as commissar in charge of the imperial family
1917 25 Oct/7 Nov Bolsheviks overthrow Provisional Government
1917 17/30 Nov News of the Bolshevik coup d'état reaches Tobol'sk
1918 31 Jan/13 Feb New style calendar adopted
1918 27 Feb Imperial family put on soldiers' rations
1918 16 Apr Vasilii Iakovlev and armed detachment escort former Emperor Nicholas II, Alexandra, and Mariia Nikolaevna, accompanied by Doctor Evgenii Botkin and three servants, to Ekaterinburg, arriving on
1918 30 April and establishing the ex-imperial family at the Ipat'ev house
1918 23 May The remaining members of the ex-imperial family arrive in Ekaterinburg
1918 12-13 Jun Grand Duke Mikhail killed in supposed escape attempt
1918 16 Jun Capital punishment reintroduced
1918 16-17 Jul Execution of Nicholas II, his family, physician, and servants
1964 Death of Anna Vyrubova (b. 1884)
Scope and Contents
The Romanov Collection, 1894-1935, consists of letters, photographs, artwork, and autographs by or pertaining to the Russian imperial family, from the years 1894-1935. The vast majority of the material, however, dates from the period 1907-1918. The collection is organized into three series: Correspondence, Photographs, Other Papers. In addition to the original source materials, some folders contain research notes such as transcriptions, translations, attributions, and background information, which have been contributed by scholars over the years. While the accuracy of these notes cannot be guaranteed, they have been retained with the relevant materials as witnesses to established interpretations.
Series I. Correspondence (1913-1928) (Box 1) consists chiefly of letters written by members of the imperial family to their close friends, lady-in-waiting Anna Vyrubova (née Taneeva) and Lili Dehn, who remained in Petrograd by orders of the government when the imperial family was removed to Tobol'sk. These letters document the family's arrest at TSarskoe Selo, exile to Tobol'sk, and relocation to Ekaterinburg, where they met their death on 16-17 July 1918. The final letter is dated after April 1918, almost three months before the death of the imperial family. Their letters chiefly concern details of the imperial family's everyday existence, news about mutual friends, and expressions of hope and despair, with little specific reference to the historical events taking place around them. In order to mask the senders' identity, the letters were often signed with an initial, a nickname, or, in Alexandra's case, a cross. In addition, some letters were apparently dictated to servants who then signed them with their own name (e.g., one letter is signed "Annushka" Box 1 folder 22). In these cases the traditional attribution has been followed.
There are several letters to Vyrubova from other members of the imperial entourage: one letter from the Tsarevich's tutor Pierre Gilliard, one letter from a relative of the imperial family, Anna Pavlovna Romanova, and three letters from Aleksei Volkov, Alexandra's valet, who accompanied the family to Ekaterinburg and escaped.
Also included in Series I are three miscellaneous letters: to Empress Alexandra from her lady-in-waiting Anastasiia Gendrikova; from Nicholas II to A. N. Naryshkina; and a historic letter from Grigorii Rasputin to the Emperor warning him against becoming entangled in the First World War.
Series II. Photographs (1894-1935) (Boxes 2-8) includes six photograph albums of the imperial family (numbered 2 through 7) and individual photographs of royal personages and related individuals, such as Rasputin's daughter Mariia. The albums mainly contain snapshots of the imperial family's leisure activities, ranging from hunting and tennis to sightseeing, at or near their palaces around Petersburg, their summer home Levadiia in the Crimea, Siberia, and Germany. Also included are some photos of the Emperor at state visits and parades, and of the Empress attending to men wounded in the First World War. Interspersed between these are photos of the family aboard the imperial yacht Standart. Many of the photos were taken and annotated by Anna Vyrubova; others were taken by members of the imperial family themselves. The albums are numbered 2 through 7; Album 1 is not in the collection. A detailed listing of Albums 2 and 3 is given in the Appendix. Further information about the origin of these albums can be found in The Romanov family album. Introduction by Robert K. Massie; picture research by Marilyn Pfeifer Swezey; assembled by Anna Vyrubova. (New York: Vendome Press, 1982).
Series III. Other Papers (1910-1918) (Box 9) includes one autograph album, containing the signatures of the entire royal family as well as many members of court, and several pieces of artwork by Empress Alexandra and Grand Duchess Irina Aleksandrovna.
The Restricted Fragile Papers housed in boxes 10-15 consist of the original photo albums from Series II; photographic facsimiles of the albums have been placed in the main files for general reference use.
Appendix: Inventory of the Romanov family photo albums #2 & #3
Note: These identifications were provided by Marilyn P. Swezey as part of her research for The Romanov family album (New York: Vendome Press, 1982). They have not otherwise been verified by the library. Additional corrections added 2004.
Album 2
p. 1: On the Standart, circa 1909 1. Alexis and the Empress Alexandra Feodorovna
2. The Emperor.
3. Marie and Olga.
4. Dr. Botkin and Admiral Chagin
5. Admiral Chagin and Adjutant Arseniev
6. Arseniev, Naryshkin and Grabbe
7. The Empress
8. The Empress
9. Admiral Chagin and officers of the Standart and L. Baron Buksgevden
p. 2: Ashore, in Finland 1. Admiral Niloff and the Emperor
2. Officers of the Standart
3. Nicholas with one of his daughters and officers
4. "
5. Nicholas and one of his daughters
6. Nicholas with Olga and officers Rodionov and Woronoff
7. Officers with one of the Grand Duchesses
8. Prince Waldemar of Prussia, cousin of the children
9. Arseniev.
p. 3: The rocky shore of Finland 1. The Emperor
2. Officers with Anna Vyrubova and Tatiana
3. Olga reading on the beach
4. Anna Vyrubova
5. Nicholas on the tennis court
6. Alexis with his nurse, Alexandra Tegleva (future wife of Pûna Gilliard)
7. Arseniev and Anna Vyrubova
8. Anna Vyrubova and Ira B.
p. 4: On the Standart 1. The Emperor in Admiral's uniform
2. Count Benckendorff and the Empress
3. The Empress with Tatiana, Alexis and Olga
4. The Emperor and Admiral Niloff
5. Arrival of the Swedish king and queen (Gustav August V and Maud)
6. Arrival of the Swedish king on deck
7. On the deck of the Swedish ship, officers at attention
p. 5: Going ashore 1. Nicholas, Olga, and Anna in the launch
2. Nicholas and Alexis with the sailors of the Standart
3. The Emperor and Adjutant Grabbe
4. Nicholas at tennis
5. The tennis party - Anna and the emperor, officers Drenteln and Woronoff
6. The Emperor and Anna on the tennis court
7. Tatiana (Gr. Duchess)
8. Nicholas
9. Tatiana and Olga
p. 6: Ashore 1. The Imperial family seen in a launch going ashore
2. The Emperor
3. Anastasia near the tennis court
4. The Emperor
5. Nicholas and one of his daughters
6. Tatiana and Anna with officers in background
7. Nicholas and Tatiana
8. Emperor, Tatiana and Anastasia
9. The Emperor
p. 7: On board the Standart 1. Nicholas and Alexandra on deck
2. Alexis
3. Olga, Paul Woronoff, Tatiana, and Drenteln reading Tatiana's palm and Anastasia
4. Olga, Woronoff, Tatiana, Anastasia, and Drenteln
5. The Empress and Alexis
6. The Empress and Marie, Olga in the background
p. 8: Ashore, playing tennis 1. Nicholas
2. "
3. "
4. Olga
5. Anna playing tennis with the Tsar and officers
6. Nicholas
7. Nicholas, Anna, and sailors in background
8. Anna and Nicholas
9. Tennis court - 2 players
p. 9: Tennis, ashore 1. Launches from the Standart with sailors and officers
2. Nicholas on the tennis court
3. Anna and an officer
4. Officers with the Emperor, Anna and Marie
5. Officers, Woronoff and Rodionov, with the Emperor
6. ______, Anna, the Emperor, Drenteln, and Woronoff
7. The Emperor, his daughters, and officers playing tennis
8. Admiral Niloff, the Emperor, Olga, and officers
9. Anastasia looking mischievous
p. 10: Ashore 1. Nicholas
2. "
3. Nicholas and Anastasia
4. Anastasia swinging, with officers
5. Officers scaling a rock
6. Alexis with Derevenko (sailor assigned to look after him) and friends playing soldier
7. Nicholas
8. Tatiana and Paul Woronoff
9. Nicholas
p. 11: On the Standart 1. Nicholas and Alexandra
2. Nicholas and Alexandra on deck
3. "
4. Alexandra
5. The Emperor on deck with his children, Anna, and officers.
6. The Empress with Alexis and Olga
7. The Empress
8. Nicholas and Alexis
9. The Empress
p. 12: On the Standart 1. Officers with the Grand Duchesses, Anna and Baroness Buxhoeveden (lady-in-waiting)
2. Anna and the Empress
3. Admiral Chagin
4. Anastasia with two officers
5. The Standart
6. Officers of the Standart with Dr. Botkin (holding cane)
7. The Emperor
8. Launches from the Standart with the Grand Duchesses and sailors coming ashore
9. Alexandra with her four daughters: Marie, Olga, Tatiana, and Anastasia; lower Dacha-Aleksandria (Peterhof) (postcard)
p. 13: On the deck of the Standart 1. The Emperor and his daughters and two ladies-in-waiting with officers of the Standart
2. Alexis with Baron Fredericks and officers of the Standart
3. The Emperor and his children with officers of the Standart and two ladies-in-waiting
p. 14 1. Tatiana, Anna, Olga, the Empress, and Marie with three officers.
2. Woronoff, Rodionov, Butakov, and the Emperor after tennis
3. The Emperor after tennis
4. "
5. The Alexander Palace at Tsarskoe Selo - main residence of the family, a rear view showing windows of the family quarters
p. 15: On the Standart 1. Nicholas and Alexis on deck
2. Nicholas and Baron Fredericks
3. Nicholas and Alexis
4. The Empress receiving the greetings of the officers - the Emperor and Dr. Botkin in background
5. Anastasia with Dr. Botkin, officers and ladies-in-waiting
6. Olga
7. Alexandra coming up ship's stairs
p. 16: On the Polar Star (the Dowager Empress's yacht) 1. Nicholas on deck
2. The launch from the Standart arriving
3. Nicholas on deck
4. Nicholas, Olga, Tatiana, Marie, and Anastasia
5. The Emperor with his mother, Dowager Empress Marie Feodorovna
6. Dowager Empress Marie with Nicholas and his four daughters, Olga, Tatiana, Marie, and Anastasia
7. The Emperor and his daughters on deck with officers, ladies-in-waiting, and a priest (picture taken by the Dowager Empress)
p. 17: "22 July, on the Polar Star" (the namesday of the Dowager Empress) 1. Alexandra surrounded by her daughters, Tatiana, Marie, Olga and Anastasia - Baron Fredericks
2. The Grand Duchesses and officers in a dance on deck 3. Tatiana and an officer in the dance
4. Olga and an officer in the dance
p. 18: On the Standart and ashore 1. The Emperor and his mother, Empress Maria Feodorovna
2. The Empress
3. The Emperor and his mother, Empress Maria Feodorovna
4. The Emperor
5. A lady-in-waiting
6. The Emperor and his mother, Empress Maria Feodorovna
7. Alexis and friends playing soldier, Derevenko in background
p. 19: On deck of the Standart 1. The Empress
2. Nicholas with an officer, Anastasia in background
3. Alexandra holding her needlework
4. Alexis
5. Alexandra
6. Alexis
p. 20 1. Alexandra and Anna ashore
2. Nicholas descending into a manhole on deck
3. Alexandra on deck
4. "
5. Tatiana with Prince Waesemar of Prussia and officers
6. Marie and the Empress
7. Rodionov
8. "
p. 21: The Standart 1. The Empress on deck
2. The sailor crew of the Standart
3. The Empress on deck
4. The Empress in a stateroom
5. The Emperor ashore
6. The Empress and Alexis in a stateroom
7. The Empress on deck
8. "
p. 22: "The staterooms of Their Majesties on the Standart" 1. The Empress's salon, showing chintz covered furniture
2. The Empress's desk, in her stateroom
3. The Emperor's desk in his study
4. The Emperor's library table and cabinet
p. 23: The Standart 1. The Empress on deck
2. The Empress's boudoir, with icons, chintz and wicker furniture
3. The Emperor
4. The Emperor and his children on deck with officers of the Standart
5. "
p. 24: "Moscow 1912 - the centennial of the Battle of Borodino" postcards 1. View of the Borodino centennial celebration, 26 August 1912, on the battlefield
2. The Emperor and his children at the Imperial reviewing stand, Borodino battlefield
3. The Imperial family receiving bread and salt from a Moscow peasant delegation as they arrive by train for the Borodino Jubilee ceremonies
4. The processional entry of the Imperial family through the Iberian gate into the Kremlin for the Borodino celebration
p. 25: Moscow 1912 and Peterhof 1. Procession of the Imperial family to the Uspensky Cathedral through Red Square in the Kremlin - Borodino Jubilee
2. View of the Kremlin from the Moscow River, showing the walls, towers and cathedrals
3. View of the Chudov Monastery in the Kremlin and Nikolskii Palace (later destroyed in the revolution), with surrounding cathedrals (St. Ivan's)
4. The Dowager Empress Marie (in striped suit) with companions
5. Alexandria Cottage, Peterhof- Dacha of Empress Maria Feodorovna
p. 26: Borodino Jubilee 1. The Emperor and his daughters in the liturgical procession on the battlefield of Borodino, 26 August 1912, postcard
2. The Empress and Alexis in a carriage with Anna Vyrubova at the Borodino ceremony, 26 August, postcard
3. Regiments passing in review on the battlefield - the Emperor is barely visible on the left
4. Nicholas and Alexandra with three of their daughters
5. The Imperial procession down the Red Staircase to the Uspensky Cathedral, Borodino Jubilee, postcard
6. View from the deck of a ship, a battleship passing in review
p. 27: "Sarov" 1. The Imperial children with their aunt Princess Victoria of Battenberg, at Peterhof- lower Dach-Aleksandria
2. An officer and ladies-in-waiting (Lili Dehn, second from left)
3. "Poniataievo"
4. "
5. "The Rev. Abbess"
6. Sarov, showing the cathedral and monastery
7. View near Sarov
p. 28: Sarov 1. A cathedral within the monastery
2. Sarov Pustyn - the spring of Father Seraphim (canonized at Sarov in 1903), postcard
3. Cathedral of Sarov
4. Peasant children of the town
5. View through the monastery gate
6. The Cathedral
7. Wayside shrine near Sarov
8. An "izba" (peasant house) in the forest near Sarov
p. 29 1. The monastery of Sarov, showing walls and cathedrals
2. The Cathedral of Sarov
3. The monastery
4. A shrine in the woods at Sarov
5. Spala (the Tsar's hunting lodge in Poland) -"the Pilitsa River"
6. View of the Pilitsa River
p. 30: "Spala 1912" 1. Field church of the hunting lodge (the striped tent)
2. "The palace"
3. Anastasia and a peasant girl in local dress
4. Tatiana playing tennis
p. 31: Spala 1912 1. Front view of the lodge
2. Bridge across the River Pilitsa
3. The countryside, looking towards the river
p. 32: Spala 1912 1. "The palace at Spala"
2. Deer shot at the hunt
3. An officer on a footbridge at Spala
4. Two friendly rabbits
5. Thatched shelter at Spala
6. The day's shoot, laid out in front of the lodge
p. 33: Spala 1912 1. "Her Majesty's drawing room"
2. "
3. The Emperor conferring with officers
4. Sentry in front of the lodge
5. The field church
6. The Emperor and his officers
7. Adjutant Ermolov
8. The Emperor with his officers
p. 34: Spala 1912 1. The Emperor in Cossack uniform, with his day's shoot
2. "
3. The Emperor with an aide in front of the lodge
4. The head of the deer shot by the Emperor, with a label attached to the antler
5. The lodge at Spala
6. The day's shoot
p. 35: Spala 1912 1. The Emperor in Cossack uniform
2. "
3. "
4. Nicholas and Alexandra with their four daughters on the front steps of Spala
5. The Emperor in Cossack dress
6. Cossacks in attendance at an outdoor Mass
7. The Emperor with Cossacks and two of his daughters
p. 36: Spala 1912 1. The Emperor
2. The Emperor, Prince Orloff and his suite of officers and Baron Fredericks, Pr. Drenteln
3. Olga and Tatiana with Princess Irene of Prussia, their aunt (sister of Alexandra)
4. Anastasia
5. Irene, the four Grand Duchesses and riding group
6. Officers in attendance to the Emperor
p. 37: Spala 1912 1. The Emperor and guests
2. Guests watching the shoot
3. "
4. "
5. The Empress and her sister Irene at the hunt
6. Scene at the hunt
7. The Empress
8. Alexandra and Irene in a carriage at the hunt
p. 38: Spala 1912 1. The Emperor
2. The lodge
3. Nicholas and Tatiana
4. Tatiana playing tennis
5. Tennis group, Anna Vyrubova at far right
6. Local peasant children in costume (Polish)
7. Tennis group, Anna in the center, Drenteln, Volkov
p. 39: Spala 1912 1. Officers on the lawn in front of the lodge
2. The lodge
3. "
4. View of the river at Spala
5. Olga, Anna, and the Emperor
6. River view
7. Alexandra with her sister, Irene
8. A tennis game at Spala
9. Princess Irene of Prussia
p. 40: Spala 1912 1. Alexandra, exhausted and in despair (Alexis suffered a near fatal attack of hemophilia during this time)
2. The porch at Spala
3. Side view of the house
4. Woods surrounding the lodge
5. Alexandra on the porch
6. The field church
7. Marie and Anastasia
8. The Emperor
9. Marie and Anastasia
p. 41: Spala 1912 1. The Empress
2. The river Pilitsa
3. An officer at tennis
4. Marie on the footbridge
5. Nicholas in Cossack uniform
6. Nicholas and Alexandra reading some of the many telegrams that began to arrive concerning Alexis's illness - prayers and wishes for his recovery
p. 42: "Tsarskoe Selo 1912 - 1913, winter" 1. View of the Feodorovsky Cathedral in the snow
2. A shrine in the park at Tsarskoe Selo
3. The snow-covered shrine
4. The front of the Feodorovsky Cathedral (built by Nicholas and only recently completed at that time, the cathedral was partially destroyed during WWII and Soviet period)
5. Side entry of the cathedral
6. Another side entry, showing the cathedral's architectural detail in the style of early medieval Russian churches
7. Icons over the doorway of the cathedral
8. Nicholas with his daughters and sister Olga (third from left), a lady-in-waiting and officer with sleds
9. Alexandria sliding downhill - the white tower "Belaya Bashnya" in the background
p. 43: Tsarskoe Selo, winter 1912-1913, Alexander Palace, children's quarters 1. Olga and the Empress sewing in the girls' room
2. Alexandra and Alexis on a chaise in the girls' room
3. Nicholas reading aloud at the bedside of Tatiana, who was recuperating from an illness
4. Alexandra at the bedside of Tatiana
5. Alexis sitting beside Tatiana
6. "
7. Tatiana in her bed, recuperating
8. Olga reading to Anastasia
9. Nicholas sitting in the girls' room
p. 44: Alexander Palace, children's quaters and balcony 1. Alexis wearing a leg brace, his knee still bent from his illness at Spala
2. Olga
3. The Empress's wheelchair on her balcony
4. Tatiana sitting on the Empress's balcony
5. Anastasia and Olga
6. Tatiana
7. Nicholas and Alexis in uniform on the Empress's balcony
8. "
9. Anastasia in Nicholas and Alexis' bedroom
p. 45: Tsarskoe Selo 1. The Emperor and Alexis on the Empress's balcony
2. Olga and Marie on the balcony in fur-trimmed suits
3. Tatiana and the Empress in the mauve boudoir
4. Olga and Tatiana with three friends
5. "
6. "
7. Alexandra in her mauve boudoir
8. Alexis and Anastasia with Marie, Olga and Tatiana in the mauve boudoir
9. Tatiana and Alexis in the mauve boudoir with Empress in double exposure
p. 46 1. Alexandra and her daughters with a guest
2. Dowager Empress Marie Feodorovna
3. The Empress and Anna Vyrubova
4. Nicholas and Alexandra with one of their regiments
5. The Empress on horseback
6. Anastasia and Marie
7. The Empress in regimental uniform
p. 47: In the park at Tsarskoe Selo 1. The Imperial family, Alexis on his bicycle
2. "
3. Nicholas and his children
4. "
5. Nicholas with Olga, Tatiana and Marie in canoes
6. Nicholas and Alexis
7. Rowing up the canal
8. Nicholas and his children canoeing
9. Alexis rowing
p. 48 1. Two unidentified little girls
2. Anna in the park at Tsarskoe Selo
3. The Grand Duchesses in the park at Tsarskoe Selo
4. Anna's sister, Alya, with her children
5. "
6. "
7. "
8. "
p. 49 1. Anna's sister, Alya, with her children
2. "
3. "
4. "Library of the Rozhdestvensky's"
5. The Rozhdestvensky's
Back cover: "Dr. Rauchfuss, drawn by Veliapolsky (head of the estate) Spala 1912"
Album 3 (1914 - 1915)
p. 1: "Sevastopol 1914" 1. Tatiana
2. Anastasia
3. The Standart in Sevastopol
4. The coastline of the Black Sea, the Crimea
5. Olga, Tatiana and Marie
6. Foliage of the Crimea
p. 2: "Livadia, spring 1914" 1. Court attendants in front of the palace
2. Tatiana and Olga
3. The Emperor reviewing the troops of the Black Sea Fleet
4. The arrival of the Imperial family by automobile
5. The Emperor stepping out of his automobile
6. "The blessing of the sanatorium established by Their Majesties"
7. The Emperor (back to camera) in attendance at the service at the sanatorium.
p. 3: "Oreander" 1. Olga in a wisteria arbor
2. The Empress
3. The church at Oreander
4. Marie, Tatiana, and Anastasia
5. Tatiana and Olga